Guide to the William J. Gaughan Collection, 1887-2000 (Bulk 1940-1980) AIS.1994.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Steel Production and Plant Operations, 1935-1981; IV.
  - Strikes -- Production Shutdown and Startup, 5.
    - Miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Management, ca. 1930-1983; V.
  This series documents various management concerns including personnel supervision, worker assistance, and worker negotiations. The contents also include directories and organization charts that illustrate management hierarchies and miscellaneous correspondence written to and from managing personnel.
  - Management -- General, 1.
    - Visit to South Works and Gary Plants, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Personnel Memos and Correspondence, 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Homestead Works Personnel Transfers from Mill Clerical to Production Planning, April 1953 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous personnel directories (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Union/Management meetings, Homestead Works, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Strike Timeline, 1946-1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Management Information and Control Systems, Homestead Works, July 1, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Employee Assistance Program, Homestead Works (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Jeopardy/Exception survey, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - William J. Gaughan Weekly Activity Reports, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Homestead Works Management Organization Chart, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Chief Clerk's Book (copy), ca 1910 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Personnel Appraisal Forms (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, ca 1930-ca 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 2.
    - Correspondence, re: bridge construction and patents, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, re: steelworker negotiations (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous inter-organizational correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Binders, Bound Materials, and Publications, ca. 1940-ca. 1990; VI.
  This series is organized by format rather than subject. Most materials in this series are publications or official reports produced by The U.S. Steel Corporation regarding topics including accident prevention, steel products, employee appraisal procedures, steel making methods, anti-trust legislation, annual reports, and U.S. Steel advertising. Other materials relate to various aspects of general steel production or, more specifically, steel production in Pittsburgh.
  - Job Evaluation Manual, Revised, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Modern Steel Providing Methods" by R.W. Graham, Assistant Superintendent of Munhall Plant, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - U.S.S. Calliroy T-1 Steel Product Information, ca 1954 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Reports from U.S. Steel for Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Principles of Accident Prevention, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Principles of Accident Prevention, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Principles of Accident Prevention, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Principles of Accident Prevention, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - This is Steel: Personnel Services -- Training and Development, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Management Appraisal Program, 1971 and 1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - U.S. Steel News, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Steel Corporation annual reports, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Focus (Carnegie Mellon University Publication), 1982-1983 and 1995 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Carnegie Magazine, Special Issue with Andrew Carnegie Recording, July/August 1985 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets and publications from U.S. Steel (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets and publications from U.S. Steel (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Steel Plant Design Series: Steel-melting Furnaces, 1956 (Box 7, Volume 1)
  - "Quality Management Program," Four Day Seminar, 1981 (Box 7, Volume 2)
  - U.S. Steel Advertising Film Library, undated (Box 7, Volume 3)
  - U.S. Steel Advertising Film Library, undated (Box 7, Volume 4)
  - First Helper's Manual, 1956 (Box 7, Volume 5)
  - Fundamentals of Physical Metallurgy, 1952 (Box 7, Volume 6)
- Topical, 1999; VII.
  This series contains material donated by William J. Gaughan in 1999. These materials include information about the 12,000 ton press, brief facts about steel making processes, and a map of The Homestead Works prepared by the National Park Service in 1965.
  - 12,000 ton Press Information (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - List of Homestead Steel Company Achievements by Date (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Map of Homestead District Works Prepared by National Park Service (copy), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Maps, Plans and Charts, 1903-ca. 1970; VIII.
  Contained in this series are maps and plans of Carnegie Steel and U.S. Steel properties, blue prints of mills, drawings of equipment, and statistical charts of products made at Homestead between 1935 and 1964. Materials too large for folders are stored in an oversize box (box 8). Related materials can also be found in Series XII.
  - Homestead Works Plant Maps, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Homestead Works Plant Maps, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Information Complied for Organization Committee, Carnegie-Steel Corporation; Includes Plant Layout, Working Force, Equipment, and Procedure for the Plate and Structural Finishing Mills", March 21, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Map Showing Properties of U.S. Steel Corporation (copy), 1903 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Blueprints of U.S. Steel Duquesne Works, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reference Drawings of Water Gauge, Edgar Thomson Works, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Maps and Plans (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Plant Maps, Homestead Works, 1928-1944; 8 items (Map-case 12, Drawer 1)
  - Product Statistics, 1935-1964; 29 items (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Product statistics for the Homestead District Works organized according by month.
  - Product Statistics, 1937-1952; 16 items (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Working copies of product statistics for the Homestead District Works organized by month.
  - Plans for Edgar Thomson Steel Works and Blast Furnaces (copy), 1890 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Edgar Thomson Works Rolling Mill, practice development of sections from Ingot to Finished Product (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bloom and Structural Charts, Homestead District Works (11 charts), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Defense Plant Layout (2 plans), ca. 1943 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - General plan of Works showing course for visitors to follow through Mil l (4 plans), 1912 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Negatives, 1941-ca. 1974; IX.
  The Negative Series consists of nearly 21,000 negatives, the majority being 4 x 5 negatives, taken between 1941-1974. The negatives depict both plant and community activity. Captured in these images are plant machinery, workers, strikes, safety and accident concerns, and social activities. Employees are depicted on the job and in their roles in family and community life. These negatives also contain images of World War II production, morale campaigns in the mill, and female employees during the war.
  - Negatives, 1941-1944 (Box 8a)
  - Negatives, 1944-1945 (Box 9)
  - Negatives, 1946-1947 (Box 10)
  - Negatives, 1948-1949 (Box 11)
  - Negatives, 1949-1950 (Box 12)
  - Negatives, 1950-1951 (Box 13)
  - Negatives, 1952-1953 (Box 14)
  - Negatives, 1954-1955 (Box 15)
  - Negatives, 1955-1958 (Box 16)
  - Negatives, 1959-1963 (Box 17)
  - Negatives, 1964-1970 (Box 18)
  - Negatives and miscellaneous, 1971-1974 (Box 19)
  - Negatives of personnel photos (Box 20)
- Photographic Prints, ca. 1890-ca. 1980; X.
  The Photographic Print Series consists primarily of 8x10 photographs produced from the negatives in Series IX, either for original Carnegie Steel or U.S. Steel use or for research use in the archives. Some prints in this series are the only copies available of images taken prior to 1941. Prints in this series are grouped in folders according to subject and are loosely separated into the following five categories: Steel Production and Plant Operations; Management and Worker Social Activities; Miscellaneous; Photograph Albums; Oversize Prints (of q size). Of particular interest in the miscellaneous category are photocopies containing William J. Gaughan's commentaries and descriptions of accompanying photographs.
  - Steel Production and Plant Operations, 1.
    - External Views of Homestead Works (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Internal Views of Edgar Thomson Works (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Open Hearth Slags (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Open Hearth Description (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Open Hearth #1 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Open Hearth #2 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Open Hearth #3 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Open Hearth #4 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Open Hearth #4 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Open Hearth #5 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Open Hearth Various (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Blast Furnace (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Carrie Furnace (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Carrie Furnace #4 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Carrie Furnaces, Various Numbers (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - 32" Mill (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - 35" Structural Mill (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - 44" Mill (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - 52" Mill (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - 54" Mill (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - 100" Mill (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - 110" Mill (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - 140" Mill (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - 160" Mill (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Structural Mill, Various (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Structural Mill, 1926-1927 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Centralized Shipping (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Various Shops (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Weld Shop (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Machine Shop (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Boiler Shop (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Saw Shop (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Howard Axle Works (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Schoen Wheel and Axle Works, McKees Rocks, PA (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Wheel and Axle Division (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Testing Machines (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Ingot Production and Shaping (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Homestead Tie Plant (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Metallurgical and Production Planning (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Metallurgical Lab Photos (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Heat Treating and Forge Maintenance (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Forge Division (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Presses (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Outstanding Safety Record: Power and Fuel Division (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Saw Shop: Structural Division Outstanding Safety Record (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Safety Campaigns (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - "Zero Defects" campaign (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - World War II Years (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - World War II Years (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Navy "E" Awards (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Armor Ballistic Tests (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Korean War (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Steel Design and Engineering Seminar, April 27-28, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Steel Production Conference, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Clearance Conference, Homestead, November 1950 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Management and Worker Social Activities, 2.
    - Various Presentations and Awards (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Steamer Trophy at McKees Rocks Bank, August 1950 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Photos of Management Golf Tournament, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Superintendent Club Golf Part, Edgewood Country Club, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - McIlvried Golf Party, Smith Hills, July 18, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - McIlvried Golf Party, South Hills Country Club, August 14, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - McIlvried 1951 Cup Tournament score card (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Homestead-Youngstown Division Superintendents Golf Parties, various (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - J.A. Hagan Cup Tournament Poster (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - H.G. McIlvried's Party for Superintendents and Assistant Superintendents at Edgewood Country Club, July 21, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Superintendent party, Webster Hall, February 1954 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - H.G. McIlvried (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Accounting Department Supervisory Group, January 30, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Softball Champs, Supervisor's Picnic, June 1950 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Supervisors Corn Roast, September 1950 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Spring Dance Supervisor's Club (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Supervisor's Club Party, Bill Greens, January 1950 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Supervisor's Club Party, Bill Greens, March 29, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Supervisor's Club Installation of Officers, Webster Hall, February 1954 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Officials Supervisor's Club, October 1954 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Supervisor's Election of Officers, Webster Hall; Arthur Bald, President, January 1955 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Installation of Officers Supervisor's Club, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Management Club (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Management Club (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Color Portrait of H.G. McIlvried (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Charles M. (Michael) Schwab (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Homestead Superintendents (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Superintendents Mansion, Edgar Thomson Works (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Homestead Works, General Superintendent's Home (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Employees, Group Photos (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Employees (Management), Individual Photos (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Employee Photos, Various (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Employee Photos, Various (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - African-American Employees, Various Prints (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - African-American Preachers and Employees (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Union Activities (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Photos of Homestead Neighborhoods and Homes (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - St. Nicholas Church (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Tent Movies, "Miracle in Paradise Valley" (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Homestead Chorus (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Ladies Home Journal Photo Shoot (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Pittsburgh Powerhouse (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Local Sports Teams (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - 8th St. Cafeteria (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - General Office Building Fire, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Construction, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Edgar Thomson Photos, Various (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Dorothy in Duquesne (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Union Railroad (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Theater Guild "On-the-Air," Syria Mosque, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Supervisor's Magazine Pictures, "Responsibility" (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Filming of 100" Mill, Roland Reed Productions, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - Product and Plant Promotion (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - Photos for 48" Mill 50th Anniversary, April 16, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Photographs taken by Association Photographers for use on back cover of Photographic Magazine, March 1949 (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - Christening of Homestead Passenger Ferry (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - Largest Stainless Steel Plate with Phyllis Anderson (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - U.S.S. Corporation Backdrop for Ocean City, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 3.
    - Miscellaneous Photos of U.S. Steel Corporation Displays (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Prints Identified (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Prints, 1936-1947 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Prints, 1938-1939 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Prints with Commentary by William Gaughan (Box 23, Folder 6-11)
    - Unidentified Prints (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified Prints (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Mounted Photos of Edgar Thomson Works Lab and Superintendent Club, 1981-1914 and 1912 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Color Proofs including Edgar Thomson Blast Furnace (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Color Prints, View of Mill from across river, October 1974 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Color Prints, MESTA 100,000 Ton Press (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Color Prints, Christmas Decorations (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Color Prints, Close up of Steel Beams (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Color Prints, Steel Slabs Cooling (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Color Prints, Various Prints of Blast Furnaces and Casting (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Color Prints, Various Outside Views of Mill (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - 1892 Homestead Strike with Militia Encampment on Hillside (from materials added in 1999) (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Homestead Views 1988-93 (Box 27, Folder 1-7)
    - William J. Gaughan at Steel Mill, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
    - William J. Gaughan Collection Donation (Box 27, Folder 9-10)
    - William J. Gaughan Presentations (Box 27, Folder 11-14)
    - William J. Gaughan Presentation Reference Material (Box 27, Folder 15-25)
    - Carnegie Phipps & Company Ltd., 1887 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Homestead Steel (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Replicas from Stevens-Robertson Galleries Collection (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Photographic Albums, 4.
    - Views of 100" Mill (Box 24, Volume 1)
    - Views of Carrie Furnace (Box 25, Volume 1)
  - Oversize Photographic Prints, 5.
    - Homestead Works (view from hillside) (Oversize 26, Item 1)
    - Homestead Works (view from above Monongahela River, near Homestead Hi-Level Bridge) (Oversize 26, Item 2-3)
    - Homestead Works (view from above Monongahela River) (Oversize 26, Item 4)
    - Homestead Works (view from near Mesta toward Homestead Hi-Level bridge) (Oversize 26, Item 5)
    - Mesta Machine Plant (view from above Monongahela River) (Oversize 26, Item 6)
    - Homestead Works (view from above Monongahela River toward mill and surrounding community) (Oversize 26, Item 7-8)
    - Homestead Works (view from above Mesta toward Homestead Hi-Level Bridge) (Oversize 26, Item 9)
    - Mesta Machine Works (view from Monongahela River) (Oversize 26, Item 10)
    - Edgar Thomson Works (view form above, towards Monongahela River) (Oversize 26, Item 11)
    - Edgar Thomson Works (view from above Monongahela River, towards mill, after 1957) (Oversize 26, Item 12)
    - Edgar Thomson Works (view from above Kennywood, across Monongahela River, toward Mill) (Oversize 26, Item 13)
    - Duplicate of folder #12 (Oversize 26, Item 14)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works (Oversize 26, Item 15)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works, Carrie Blast Furnaces (Oversize 26, Item 16)
    - Aerial view of unidentified plant (Oversize 26, Item 17)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works, 1950s (Oversize 26, Item 18)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works, upper mills in west end, post 1958 (Oversize 26, Item 19)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works (Oversize 26, Item 20)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works (Oversize 26, Item 21)
    - Aerial view of Homestead Works, with 45" mill, foundry, 32" mill, old physical lab, and old 119" plate mill building (Oversize 26, Item 22)
    - Superintendent of Edgar Thomson Works with Phil Murray (Head of USW) and two unidentified men. On a good will tour to encourage harmony between management and labor. (Oversize 26, Item 23)
    - Forging (Oversize 26, Item 24)
    - Charging an open heart furnace (Oversize 26, Item 25)
    - Testing (Oversize 26, Item 26)
    - Teeming (Oversize 26, Item 27)
    - 50,000 lbs. capacity soaking pit crane (Oversize 26, Item 28)
    - McIlvried portrait inside mill [print is missing from its original folder, duplicate may be found in FF 94:3/22/28], 1950 (Oversize 26, Item 29)
    - Superintendent Charles Pinkey portrait (Oversize 26, Item 30)
    - J.L. Perry Portrait (Oversize 26, Item 31)
    - Work crews, 30" slab and 48" plate mills (Oversize 26, Item 32)
    - General superintendents - control operations (Oversize 26, Item 33)
    - Portrait of Benjamin F. Fariless, President and CEO of U.S. Steel (Oversize 26, Item 34)
    - Automatic ladle addition equipment, open hearth, ca. 1958 (Oversize 26, Item 35)
    - Superintendent's Club, Homestead Steel Works (Oversize 26, Item 36)
    - Superintendents [placed at bottom of box due to size], 1898 (Oversize 26, Item 37)
    - Edgar Thomson blast furnace and ladles, undated (Oversize 26, Item 38)
    - Aerial view of Edgar Thomson Works, undated (Oversize 26, Item 39)
    - Edgar Thomson Works, 1916 (Oversize 26, Item 40)
    - Edgar Thomson Works, 1912 (Oversize 26, Item 41)
    - The building of an open hearth at Edgar Thomson Works, 1914 (Oversize 26, Item 42)
    - Back end of open hearth, Edgar Thomson Works, 1913 (Oversize 26, Item 43)
    - Aerial view of Edgar Thomson Works, 1958 (Oversize 26, Item 44)
    - 1892 Homestead Strike, Militia on Hillside. Photo possibly taken by BLH Dabbs. (Oversize 26, Item 45)
- Motion Picture Films, ca. 1956-ca. 1974; XI.
  The Motion Picture Films Series contains films produced for the U.S. Steel Corporation to demonstrate steel production techniques, train new employees, promote safety, and address management concerns.
  - The Heating of Capped Steel. U.S.S Metallurgical Process Control, 16mm, B&W, optical audio; 400+ feet (Oversize 26, Reel 1)
  - Steel and America: a New Look..., Produced by Walt Disney production for American Steel Institute; Copyright 1974; Art Director - A Kendall O'Connor; Story by William R. Bosche; Director - Les Clark; Associate Producer- Ken Peterson; 16 mm, color, optical audio; approx. 900 ft. (Oversize 26, Reel 2)
  - Steel and America: a New Look... (Oversize 26, Reel 3)
  - Knowing's Not Enough, Director- Jack Tilles; Producer- Wilding Picture Productions, Inc.; Copyright 1956; 16mm, color, optical audio; 950+ feet (Oversize 26, Reel 4)
  - Knowing's Not Enough [missing beginning of film] (Oversize 26, Reel 5)
  - The Search for a Better Way: Report to Management on the Findings of the Management Questionnaire, Presented by C.F. Hood, President of U.S.S; Produced by Wilding Picture Productions; 16mm, B&W, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 6)
  - The Search for a Better Way: Report to Management on the Findings of the Management Questionnaire (Oversize 26, Reel 7)
  - Yeah, Director- Samuel Beall and Orlando Lippert; Produced by Wilding Picture Productions; Copyright 1958; 16mm, color, optical audio; 700 feet (Oversize 26, Reel 8)
  - The Hot Rolling of Steel Sheets, The Making and Shaping of Steel Series, Copyright 1961; The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 9)
  - The Electric Arc Furnace, The Making and Shaping of Steel Series, Produced by John Sutherland; Copyright 1960, The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 10)
  - The Blast Furnace, The Making and Shaping of Steel Series, Produced by John Sutherland; Copyright 1960, The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio; 300 feet (Oversize 26, Reel 11)
  - The Blast Furnace [missing beginning of film] (Oversize 26, Reel 12)
  - Chemistry of Iron and Steel, The Making and Shaping of Steel Series, Produced by John Sutherland; Copyright 1960, The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio; 500 feet (Oversize 26, Reel 13)
  - Oxygen Film, OH Department of Homestead Works (Oversize 26, Reel 14)
  - Semi-Finished Steel, The Making and Shaping of Steel Series, Produced by John Sutherland; Copyright 1960, The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 15)
  - The Open Hearth Furnace, The Making and Shaping of Steel Series, Produced by John Sutherland; Copyright 1960, The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 16)
  - Tension Testing, Produced by the Division of Visual Aids, U.S. Office of Education; Copyright 1974, Audio Products, Inc; 16 mm, color, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 17)
  - Treasure Chest, Copyright 1956, The United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, color, optical audio (Oversize 26, Reel 18)
  - Hooking the Skull Scraper, Steel Plant Methods Improvements; United States Steel Corporation; 16mm, B&W, silent; 250 feet (Oversize 26, Reel 19)
  - Steel by Stopwatch, Jones and Laughling Corporation; Written by Frank Siegel, Storycraft Inc; Produced and directed by Julius Potocsny; Continental Motion Picture Co., Inc; 16mm, color, optical audio; 900 feet (Oversize 26, Reel 20)
  - Pouring, Babbit Bearings, A Marshall Maintenance Production; 16mm, color; 600 feet (Oversize 26, Reel 21)